Isabela Oliveira da Silva

⊕ <u>Portfólio</u> ⊅

Lattes 7

Linkedin 🗷

Front-end Developer | Designer based in Brazil

Professional specialized in UI and UX design and front-end development, with over 3 years of experience in building and maintaining websites. My focus is on creating accessible and high-performance digital experiences for users, combining my passion for design with strong technical programming skills.

Work Experiences

Desenvolvedora Front-end I, Turbo Partners 2023 ~ Currently

Atuação como Desenvolvedora Front-end I em projetos digitais para a Turbo Partners.

UI/UX Designer and Front-end Developer, for/ma - UFES 2022 ~ Currently

Researcher at Forma Lab, where I work as a user experience researcher, interface designer, and front-end developer in the Entrepreneur's Dashboard project, a statistical data platform for entrepreneurship purposes, for ADERES.

Front-end Developer, Webicos Collective 2022 ~ Currently

Experience as a front-end developer in various freelance projects, ranging from landing pages and personal portfolios to news portals, at Webicos, an independent Design and Development Collective.

Junior Web Designer, iOBEE Ago 2023 - Nov 2023

Experience Web Designer Junior in digital Projects at iOBEE – Ecosystem of Digital Marketing and Technology Solutions.

Front-end Developer, Fiotec 2023

Researcher in Digital Technology and Innovation at the COMSAÚDE Hackathon, promoted by FIOTEC in collaboration with the Distrito Federal's Health Department in Brazil. Acting as a front-end developer in the project's team planning, which involves confidential information.

UI/UX Designer and Front-end Developer, LDI - SEAD/UFES 2020 ~ 2022

Web Design intern at the Instructional Design Laboratory (LDI) - SEAD/UFES. Development of websites, landing pages, and progressive web applications (PWA) for the Distance Education Superintendent's Office at UFES.

Education

Design, UFES

Completed Undergraduate Bachelor degree in Design, by the Federal University of Espírito Santo (UFES).

Isabela Oliveira da Silva

Front-end Developer | Designer based in Brazil

⊕ Portfólio ↗

in Linkedin 7

Certificates

UX Writing, 12h Plurix

Study of fundamental concepts of UX Writing, accessibility, usability and strategic design.

Introduction to Front-End Development, 19h Meta

Learning of reinforcement in HTML, CSS, and Responsive Design, among other UI Design concepts.

Advanced UI, 30h Origamid

Study of fundamental concepts of UI Design, such as typography, spacing, colors, grid, among others.

Front-End Automation with NPM, 8h Origamid

Experience with performance optimization libraries and front-end automation, such as Gulp and Jimp.

User Experience, 60h FIAP

Study of fundamental concepts of User Experience Design, focusing on accessibility, efficiency and performance during project planning.

Web Development, 148h XP Educação

Web Development Bootcamp, focusing on basic learning of Java, Python, and Javascript.

Foundations of User Experience, 18h Google

Study of fundamental concepts of UX Design, such as human-centered design and accessibility, among others.

Calculus for Systems Analyst, 160h XP Educação

Calculus Bootcamp, focusing on basic to intermediate learning with code applications.

Design Thinking, 40h FIAP

Study of fundamental concepts of Design Thinking, such as human-centered design and the creative process and planning in design.

Hiring Coders Training, 120h VTEX / Gama Academy

Intensive full-stack development training, involving everything from HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to Node.js and MySQL.

Tecnologies and tools

Figma	HTML	SASS	Wordpress	Elementor
Illustrator	CSS	React	PWAs	
Photoshop	JavaScript	Next.js	EJS	